(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-22T22:10:16.786880",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
雪が降り この夜を
Snow falls and lights up this night,
月明かりが 照らし出してく
illuminated by the moonlight.
好きなフリ とかじゃない
It's not like I'm just pretending to like you—
本当の気持ちに 初めて気付いた
for the first time, I realized my true feelings.
始まっていたんだ
It had already begun.
はじまりは いつだって 突然のストーリー
The beginning was always a sudden story—
君のこと 考えるだけで 想い溢れてく
just thinking of you makes my feelings overflow.
雪が散らめく この花束を
This bouquet where snow dances around,
抱えて祈ってる
I'm holding and praying,
君に渡せるように 指先が震える まだかな
hoping to hand it to you, my fingertips trembling—is it time yet?
待ってるね いつだって この想い 届くときを
I'll always be waiting for the moment these feelings reach you.
意味もなく 過ごしてた
I spent my days meaninglessly,
日々を変えてくれたから
because you changed those days.
夢の数だけ夢は大きくなるんだって
That dreams grow as big as the number of dreams we have,
小さな頃から知っていたはず
I'm sure I've known it since I was little.
心がブレーカーかけて立ち止まってしまっても
Even if my heart trips a breaker and comes to a halt,
ゴールは逃げたりしないから
the goal isn't going to run away from us.
一歩ずつ ゆっくりでも
Step by step, even if it's slow,
進むこと 前だけ見て
moving forward, looking only ahead.
辛くても 絶対に諦めない
Even when it's hard, I'll never give up,
だって大切な仲間がいつもそばにいるから
because my precious friends are always by my side.
明日への境界線を みんなでせーの!越えたい
Let's all cross the boundary line to tomorrow, ready, go!
繋がる絆は離れない ずっと
The bonds connecting us will never separate, forever.
空回りが雨降らし つまづきこともあるけど
Sometimes spinning our wheels brings rain and stumbles,
絶対、大丈夫!
but I'm sure we'll be fine!
そう仲間を信じて進め
Just believe in our friends and press forward.
絆が深まるほど夢は確信に変わる
The deeper our bonds, the more our dreams turn into certainty.
素敵な未来を描こうね
Let's paint a wonderful future together.
ひとつずつ 怖がらずに
One by one, without being afraid,
越えなくちゃいけない 空見上げて
looking up at the sky we must cross.
暗闇も いつかは晴れるからね
Even the darkness will clear up someday, won't it?
道に迷って落ち込む私を照らしてくれる
Illuminating me when I get lost and down.
夢との境界線へ みんなでせーの!飛び込もう
Let's all dive into the boundary line with our dreams, ready, go!
想いを繋げて未来まで続け
Connecting our feelings, let them reach into the future.
遠回りが風吹かし 倒れることもあるけど
Sometimes taking the long way around brings headwinds and falls,
ずっと一緒だよ
but we'll always be together.
さあ描いた夢まで進め
Now, let's advance toward the dream we drew.
明日への境界線を みんなでせーの!越えたい
Let's all cross the boundary line to tomorrow, ready, go!
繋がる絆は離れない ずっと
The bonds connecting us will never separate, forever.
どんな未来が待っていても 必ず隣にいるよ
No matter what future awaits us, I will always be right by your side.
どうか忘れないで
Please don't ever forget that.
さあ明日を迎えに行こう
Now, let's go welcome tomorrow.
ホッ ほら行こうぜ
Ho, hey, let's go!
そうだ みんな行こうぜ
That's right, everyone let's go!
さあ ほら歌おうぜ そうだ みんな歌おうぜ
Now, hey, let's sing! Everyone let's sing!
ホッ ほら誓おうぜ そうだ みんな誓おうぜ
Ho, hey, let's swear! Everyone let's swear!
さあ ほら愛そうぜ 最高級で愛そうぜ
Now, hey, let's love! With the highest grade!
Everybody get up! ウチらが住む
Everybody get up! The future where we live,
未来だぜ Let's get up!
Let's get up!
Everybody scream! 意味ないけど
Everybody scream! It doesn't mean much,
コンビニが好き ハハハハ
but I love convenience stores, hahaha!
久しぶりだぜ 古郷には
It's been a while, back in my hometown,
サラりシュウ帰ろ
smoothly I'll return
英会話スクール 入ったきり
Ever since I joined an English conversation school,
イケてないぜ ハハハハハ
I haven't been cool at all, hahahahaha!
ほら行こうぜ Peace! Peace!
Hey, let's go! Peace! Peace!
選挙の日って ウチじゃなぜか
For some reason in our house on election day,
投票行って 外食するんだ
we go vote and then eat out.
奇跡みたい 素敵な未来 意外なほど凄い恋愛
Like a miracle, a wonderful future, surprisingly amazing romance
Let's go! Let's go!
好きな人が 優しかった
The person I like was kind
嬉しい出来事が増えました
Happy events have increased
大事な人がわかってくれた
An important person understood me
感動的な出来事となりました
It became a touching event
That's all right!
デリバリーピザ いつも悩む
Delivery pizza, always worrying
LかMか ピザ
over L or M pizza
盛り上がり長電話は
Excited long phone calls
切りにくいね ハハハハハ
are hard to hang up on, hahahahaha!
ほら行こうぜ Peace! Peace!
Hey, let's go! Peace! Peace!
多数決じゃ 決められないのは
What cannot be decided by majority vote
恋愛のエトセトラ
is romance and all its et ceteras.
個性を使う 異性をダッシュ 普通をウォッシュ 速攻でダッシュ
Use individuality, dash for the opposite sex, wash normality, dash instantly
Let's go! Let's go!
道行く人が 親切だった
A passerby was kind
嬉しい出来事が増えました
Happy events have increased
愛しい人が 正直でした
The person I love was honest
全てを受け入れようと 感じました
I felt like accepting everything
That's all right!
青春の1ページって…
A page of youth...
(Woo Love Revolution)
乾杯BABY! 紙コップでYEAH!
Cheers, baby! With paper cups, yeah!
いいじゃない OH YES 気持ちが大事
Why not? Oh yes, feelings are key.
飾りはBABY! あるものでYEAH!
Decorations, baby! With what we have, yeah!
IN THE NIGHT OH YES アイデア勝負
In the night, oh yes, it's ideas!
愛する人よ TELL ME TELL ME
My darling, tell me, tell me.
淋しい時は BABY BABY
When you're lonely, baby, baby...
どんな人にも TELL ME TELL ME
Everyone, tell me, tell me.
あるというのは 本当なの? (Yes!)
Is that really true? (Yes!)
超超超 いい感じ 超超超超いい感じ
Super, super, super good feeling!
(Woo Love Revolution)
恋もして (Woo Baby) 仕事して (Woo Baby)
In love (Woo Baby), working (Woo Baby),
歴史きざんだ地球
history shaped on this earth.
泣いちゃった (Woo Baby) 腹へった (Woo Baby)
Crying (Woo Baby), hungry (Woo Baby),
LOVE REVOLUTION 21
(Woo Love Revolution)
行こうぜBABY! 自転車でYEAH!
Let's go, baby! By bicycle, yeah!
いいじゃない OH YES 勇気が大事
Why not? Oh yes, courage is key.
謳おうぜBABY! へたふででYEAH!
Let's sing, baby! Clumsily, yeah!
IN THE NIGHT OH YES 愛情で勝負
In the night, oh yes, it's love!
愛する人よ TELL ME TELL ME
My darling, tell me, tell me.
楽しい時は BABY BABY
When you're happy, baby, baby...
どんな色した TELL ME TELL ME
What color, tell me, tell me.
服で決めれば いいのかな? (Yes!)
Clothes should I wear? (Yes!)
超超超 いい感じ 超超超超いい感じ
Super, super, super good feeling!
(Woo Love Revolution)
恋をした (Woo Baby) 寝坊した (Woo Baby)
In love (Woo Baby), sleeping in (Woo Baby),
すべて見てきた地球
the earth has seen it all.
愛ゆえに (Woo Baby) 抱きしめた (Woo Baby)
Because of love (Woo Baby), holding you (Woo Baby),
LOVE REVOLUTION 21
この星は 美しい
This planet is so beautiful,
二人出会った地球
the earth where we met.
all together now! all together now!
みんなで恋愛革命
Love revolution for everyone!
恋をした (Woo Baby) 寝坊した (Woo Baby)
In love (Woo Baby), sleeping in (Woo Baby),
すべて見てきた地球
the earth has seen it all.
愛ゆえに (Woo Baby) 抱きしめた (Woo Baby)
Because of love (Woo Baby), holding you (Woo Baby),
LOVE REVOLUTION 21
さあ ほら行こうぜ さあみんな行こうぜ
Let's go, baby! Come on everyone, let's go!
さあ ほら歌おうぜ さあみんな歌おうぜ
Let's sing, baby! Come on everyone, let's sing!
さあ ほら近づこうぜ さあみんな近づこうぜ
Let's get close, baby! Come on everyone, get close!
さあ ほら愛そうぜ 最高級で愛そうぜ
Let's make up, baby! Let's make up with the best match!
(Woo Love Revolution)
愛する人よ TELL ME TELL ME
My darling, tell me, tell me.
淋しい時は BABY BABY
When you're lonely, baby, baby...
どんな人にも TELL ME TELL ME
Everyone, tell me, tell me.
あるというのは 本当なの? (Yes!)
Is that really true? (Yes!)
超超超 いい感じ 超超超超いい感じ
Super, super, super good feeling!
(Woo Love Revolution)
恋もして (Woo Baby) 仕事して (Woo Baby)
In love (Woo Baby), working (Woo Baby),
歴史きざんだ地球
history shaped on this earth.
泣いちゃった (Woo Baby) 腹へった (Woo Baby)
Crying (Woo Baby), hungry (Woo Baby),
LOVE REVOLUTION 21
この星は 美しい
This planet is so beautiful,
二人出会った地球
the earth where we met.
all together now! all together now!
みんなで恋愛革命
Love revolution for everyone!
(Woo Love Revolution)
ラミィ！お誕生日おめでとー！！
Lamy! Happy birthday!
やったー！
Yay!
なんだこれ！なんだこれ！
What's this? What's this?
飲むの？今日は？
Are we drinking today?
飲むの？
We are?
とりあえずね、乾杯をしよう！
Well, first, let's do a toast.
乾杯をね。
A toast!
そうね。
Right!
あの、みんなには見えないけど
Well, not everyone has one, but...
ええ、あるんですけど。
There is one.
こちらはノエルのポーションでございますよ。
This here is Noel's potion.
初めて見るの！おー！
Wait, really? My first time seeing it!
じゃあ、皆さんご一緒に、よろしいですか？
So, everyone, together...
飲みましょうか！はい！
Let's drink!
かんぱ～い！
Cheers!
うん？
Hm?
あっ！どうした？？
Wait, what?
どうしたどうした？大丈夫？おっ、うまっ！
What's wrong? Are you okay?
めちゃ爽やかな味よ。
It has such a refreshing taste!
そうなんですよ。
Indeed it does.
犬には早かったか？w
Is it too early for a dog? w
ジンベースだからね、いろんなボタニカルが
Since it's gin-based, it has various botanicals...
それが自然なナチュラルな感じがしてね。
Ah, so it's naturally botanical.
えっ、それよりさ、
Wait, also...
なんか、上にハッシュタグ的なものがさ、
There's like a hashtag thing at the top.
見えるんですけど。あ、すごいじゃん。台本どんどん飛ばしてくね。
Oh, wow. We're skipping the script completely!
やめてやめてやめて。台本読むって言ったのに。
Wait, wait, wait, wait! We were supposed to read it!
「いやぁ良いんですか？ラミィの誕生日で、
"It's fine, right? Since it's Lamy's birthday,"
ゲストに呼んで頂いたんですけど、こんなくつろいじゃって」
"and you invited me as a guest, but relaxing this much..."
「良いんですよ～！」
"It's fine~!"
あ、これラミィちゃんのセリフだったわ。「良いんですよ～！」
Ah, that was Lamy's line!
ぐだぐだや、ごめんね！
So messy!
今日はね、
Today...
え、かねてからチャンネル登録者数100万人達成したら
Well, ever since we hit 1 million subscribers,
100万円分のお酒を飲むと決めてたのでね、
we decided to drink 1 million yen worth of alcohol!
飲んじゃおうと思います！
Let's drink up!
というこで、本日のハッシュタグがこちら！
Today's hashtag is right here!
#やかまし100万円飲み会
#Yakamashi1MillionYenDrinkingParty
100万円分飲めるってことですね？
So we can drink 1 million yen worth?
てことなんですよ！
That's what it is!
てことでね、今日は、
So today...
日本酒が前半戦で、後半戦が、えー、後半戦が、えーと、ワインを、用意しております。
Japanese sake for the first half, and for the second half, um, we have prepared wine.
ワイン！そう！
Wine! That's right!
さあ、ということで、まず日本酒ということなんですけれども、
Now then, first off, we're talking about Japanese sake,
日本酒といえば！？ここで…
and speaking of sake...! Right here...
ゲストを用意しております！
We have a guest prepared!
日本酒といえば！？そう、日本酒といえば！？
Speaking of sake...! Right, speaking of sake...!
せーの！おめでとー！いぇーい！
Ready, set! Congratulations! Yay!
おめでとうございまーす！おめでとう！
Congratulations! Congratulations!
雪花さん、日本酒飲めるんすかぁ～！？
Yukisaki, can you even drink sake?!
日本酒飲めますよ、100万円分のね！！
I can drink sake! 1 million yen worth, you know!!
ちょっとね、面白い日本酒をいろいろね用意したので、
We've prepared all sorts of interesting sake,
お、お！ちょっとね、紹介していきたいと思います！
Oh! Oh! We'd like to introduce them!
やったー！
Yay!
えーちゃん、よろしくお願いします！！お！
E-chan, thank you very much!! Oh!
はい。商品の紹介は、私、ホロライブスタッフ友人Aがおこないます。
Yes. The product introduction will be conducted by Hololive staff Friend A.
やかし100万円飲み会、最初の酒は「零響 -Absolute 0-」。
#Yakami 1-Million-Yen Drinking Party, the first sake is 'Reikyo -Absolute 0-'.
精米歩合50%以下の日本酒は、まず何と呼ばれるかご存知ですか？
Do you know what sake with a rice milling ratio of 50% or less is called?
え？なんて呼ばれるんですか？
Huh? What is it called?
大吟…大吟醸！あ、大吟醸！
Dai... Daiginjo! Ah, Daiginjo!
大吟醸！そう！と、呼ばれ、あの高級酒に位置づけられるんですよ。
Daiginjo! Exactly! It's called that, and it's classified as a high-end sake.
なんとこの零響、精米歩合が0.85%！
And this Reikyo has a rice milling ratio of 0.85%!
え、そう！どこ！？ほぼない！！ほぼ削っちゃった！
Eh, really?! Where?! Almost none!! You shaved almost all of it!
お米全体のあの99.15%を削って、
Shaving off 99.15% of the entire rice grain,
残り0.85%の部分だけを使って、極限まで削られた部分だけで…
and using only the remaining 0.85%, using only the part that has been shaved to the absolute limit...
スゲェー！
That's amazing!
お米の真ん中の真ん中の真ん中の真ん中…見えな～い！
The very center of the center of the center of the rice... Can't see it~!
そうですね！
That's right!
なんとあの5297時間、221日もの時間をかけて精米…
It takes 5,297 hours, 221 days to mill...
じっくりとお酒を、あの、お米をね、磨くそうですよ。
They slowly polish the rice for the sake.
詳しいなこいつ！匠の技ですね！
You know your stuff! That is craftmanship!
メガネかけてそうだな、めがねかけてたら絶対…ふぇいって感じです。
You look like you wear glasses, if you wore glasses you'd definitely be like... 'fei'.
お値段こちら…38万5000円！
The price is... 385,000 yen!
やったー！おめでとー！
Yay! Congratulations!
大事に大事にお楽しみください。
Please enjoy it with the utmost care.
お値段ね、38万5000円！初めてそんな高い酒飲みます！
The price is 385,000 yen! I've never drunk sake that expensive!
一年分の食費くらいじゃないですか！？
Isn't that about a year's worth of food expenses?!
一年…絶妙だな、一年！
A year... That's exquisite, a year!
みんな！かーんぱーい！！かんぱーい！
Everyone! Cheers!! Cheers!
38万5000円おめでとうございまーす！
Congratulations on the 385,000 yen!
匂いがすごーい！！
The aroma is amazing!!
ラミィ、これはどんな匂いですか？
Lamy, what kind of aroma is this?
これはですね、もう削りに削り取りられたもう、雑みのないっ！
This is, well, it's been shaved and shaved down, completely free of off-flavors!
もう雑みのないっ！旨味しかない吟醸香！ですよ、これ。
Completely free of off-flavors! Daiginjo aroma with nothing but umami! That's what this is.
な、みんなね、生きてるうちに、もう嗅ぐことないよ、これ。本当！
You guys won't get to smell something like this while you're alive. Seriously!
本当にね、匂いだけで酔ってしまう、せいじんが止ま…せいじんが止まりませんね。飲みやすい！
Really, you get drunk just from the aroma, my sanity is sto... my sanity can't be stopped. It's easy to drink!
飲んだの？飲んだの？飲んじゃった…飲んだ！飲んじゃった！
You drank it? You drank it? You drank it...!
うまっ！！うま！！
Delicious!! So good!
なんか…あっ、あぁ～！
Something... ah, aaah~!
飲みやすい！
It's easy to drink!
え、なんか、せんちゃんもなんか、もしかして匂い的に無理かもしれないと思ったけど…美味いわぁ…
Wait, Sen-chan also thought she might not be able to handle the aroma, but... it's delicious...
雑みのないっ！
Completely free of off-flavors!
この、0.8だっけ、さっきの、0.85！0.85！
This, was it 0.8 earlier? 0.85! 0.85!
雑みがなくてスッキリとしてるっ！
It has no off-flavors and is crisp and clean!
これは素晴らしい一品ですけれども…めちゃくちゃ美味しいです！
This is a wonderful item... It's ridiculously delicious!
なんか、ちょっとみんな足りとなくないすか？
Doesn't it feel like everyone's still wanting more?
はい！おなかすいたなぁ～！おなかすいた！おなかすいたぁ～！
Yes! I'm getting hungry~! Hungry! So hungry~!
なんだこれ、なんか食べたいな。なんかあるのかな？
What's this, I want to eat something. Is there something?
今日はね、今回ね、ここでおつまみも！力を入れております！！
Today, this time, we've also put a lot of effort into the snacks!!
おつまみも力入ってるんですかぁ！？えーちゃん、紹介よろしくお願いします！
You put effort into the snacks too?! E-chan, please introduce them!
お待ちかね、最初のおつまみは「からすみ」。みなさんは、からスマの原料って知ってますか？
The long-awaited first snack is 'Karasumi'. Do you all know what the raw material for karasumi is?
からすみってさ…食べたことないんだけど、これって正体なに？
Karasumi... I've never eaten it, what is it really?
イカ、あれ、スミじゃないの？
Squid, wait, isn't it ink?
イカ墨ではない！
It's not squid ink!
卵巣ですよね？あ、卵巣なんだ！卵？
It's an ovary, right? Ah, an ovary! An egg?
誰の卵？カラスの？
Whose egg? A crow's?
カラス！？鳥になっちゃったw
A crow?! It became a bird lol
ボラの卵巣。 ボラって何よ？
Mullet ovary. What's a mullet?!
お魚じゃない？お魚ですね。
Isn't it a fish? It's a fish.
ボラの卵巣…え、こんなのお腹の中に入ってんだ？あれじゃない、なんかギュッてしてんじゃん、ギュッてしてんの？
Mullet ovary... Eh, this is inside its stomach? Isn't it, like, squeezed tight? Is it squeezed?
タラコとかと同じってことね！ああ、そういうことか！
It's the same as tarako! Ah, I see!
はい、そしてもう一つ行きますか！まだありますよ！
Right, shall we go to another one? There's still more!
まだあるんだ
There's still more?
もう一つなんだ？
What's the other one?
口に入れた瞬間とろける幸せ。
Instant melting bliss upon taking a bite.
続いても海の幸から一級品のウニです。
Next is top-grade uni from the sea.
テッカテカだぁ～！
It's so glossy!
おいしそう…いい色ですね
Looks delicious... What a nice color.
ラミィたん先に食べなよ
Ramy-tan, eat yours first.
そうですね、お願いします。
That's right. Go ahead, please.
じゃあちょっとウニからざばっ！と取って良い？
So, can I grab a big chunk of uni first?
あら～
Oh~
あ、ごめんね。ちょっと見えなかったかもだけど。
Ah, sorry. You might not have seen it.
どうぞ！食べてみてくださいよ。
Go ahead! Please try it.
う～ん！
Mmm!
う、う、う〜ん！！！
Mmm, mmm, mmm!!!
うに！？
Uni!?
うにうにうに！
Uni uni uni!
濃厚なウニの味、なんか臭みが全然ない！
Rich uni flavor, and no fishy smell at all!
あ、それは素晴らしい。
Ah, that's wonderful.
さすがでございます。
As expected.
待って、人生で初めてからすみ食べてみようかな。
Wait, maybe I'll try karasumi for the first time.
日本酒に合いますからね。
Because it goes well with sake.
僕はボラ…
I'm a mullet...
ボラになるはずだった…
I was supposed to become a mullet...
そんな言い方したら食べづらいじゃないですか！！
If you put it that way, it's hard to eat!!
でも気にせず食べてます。
But I'm eating it without worrying.
さあ感想はどうでしょうか？
Now, what are your thoughts?
なんじゃろ？
What could it be?
シャケみたい…
It's like salmon...
シャケ！？
Salmon!?
卵なのに身みたいってこと？
Even though it's roe, it's like fish meat?
逆になんかちょっと食べてみて！
On the contrary, try eating some!
いただきまーす
Let's eat.
いただきます。いただきます！
Let's eat. Let's eat!
イカスミ…
Squid ink...
イカスミじゃないです！
It's not squid ink!
なんだけっけ？
What was it again?
からすみ！
Karasumi!
からすみです。
It's karasumi.
どうかな？
How is it?
シャケっぽくない？
Doesn't it seem like salmon?
魚…
Fish...
なんか止まってますけど大丈夫ですか？w
It's frozen, are you okay? w
これをこの高い日本酒でかき込むこうやって
Eating this down with this expensive sake like this...
どうですか？合いますか？
How is it? Does it match?
濃厚で！
Rich!
合うー！！美味ぁーい！！
Matches!! Delicious!!
美味しすぎる
Too delicious.
ころねさん！ころねさん大丈夫ですか？
Korone-san! Korone-san, are you okay?
あ、大丈夫です！
Ah, I'm okay!
なんか水飲みたい水飲みたいモードね
Seems like you're in water-drinking mode.
これすごい飲みやすいよ！
This is super easy to drink!
ころね！？
Korone!?
スルッて
Smoothly...
ころねころね！
Korone, Korone!
早いよ早いよ！
Hurry up! Hurry up!
まだ始まったばっかりだよ！
It's only just begun!
始まったばっかりだよ！
Just begun!
コップ半分も飲んでないからね
You haven't even drunk half a cup yet.
うわそう...
Oh right...
醤油、醤油もいいよ、タマゴ
Soy sauce, soy sauce is good too, egg
こよりのよりももらいたい
I want Koyori's too.
あ、「こより」じゃねえやん
Ah, that's not "Koyori"
戌神ころね
Inugami Korone
自分をころねだってもう忘れてしまっている
She's already forgotten she's Korone.
こよりのよりももらいたいって言ってるよ
She's saying she wants Koyori's too.
大丈夫？w
You okay? w
ちょっと逃げる
Escaping a bit.
それ醤油だから！！醤油飲まないで！！
That's soy sauce!! Don't drink soy sauce!!
ここでもう1本、約50年もの間、洞窟で眠っていた日本酒。当時、鑑評会に出品する最高のお酒をビール瓶に詰めて撮っていたものだそうですよ。
Here's another: a sake that slumbered in a cave for about 50 years. It's said they filled beer bottles with the highest-grade sake entered in appraisal competitions back then.
うーん！すごい！！
Mmm! Amazing!!
歴史ありますね
It has history.
あ、じゃあこれ、瓶にビールって書いてあるけど
Ah, well, it says beer on the bottle, but...
ビールじゃない
It's not beer.
こちらがおいくらですか？
How much is this one?
30万円です！
300,000 yen!
これも30万するの！？
This costs 300,000 too!?
やばっ！
Whoa!
色がだいぶ違いますね
The color is quite different.
そう、色がね？
Yeah, the color, right?
これってなんだっけ？
What was this again?
日本酒？
Sake?
あぁ日本酒かｗ
Ah, sake w
日本酒のコーナーだから日本酒…あ、色付いてるパターンもありえるのか…
It's in the sake corner so sake... Ah, could there be colored versions too...
古酒はだいたい黄色くなりますからね
Aged sake usually turns yellow.
そうなんだ、有名な話か
Is that so, famous fact?
香りもちょっと酸っぱい感じ
The aroma also has a slightly sour feel.
匂い嗅いでみてください
Please try smelling it.
えーーー！？
Eeeee!?
え、何？
Eh, what?
匂いは何？
What's the smell?
え、酸っぱ！
Eh, sour!
酸っぱくてびっくりしたのね
You were surprised because it was sour.
びっくりした
Surprised.
バルサミコ酢？
Balsamic vinegar?
なんか黙ってますけど大丈夫ですか？
You're being quiet, are you okay?
バルサミコ酢
Balsamic vinegar
いつも以上に訛ってますけどｗ
You're speaking with a stronger accent than usual w
かんぱーい！！
Cheers!!
お味は？
How's the taste?
バルサミコ酢？
Balsamic vinegar?
良いのか？それでｗ
Is that really okay? w
バルサミコ酢？30万ですけど？
Balsamic vinegar? Even though it's 300,000 yen?
なんか古酒ならではの深い味がするんですけど、後味スッキリしてるからめちゃめちゃ飲みやすい！
It has a deep flavor unique to aged sake, but the aftertaste is clean so it's super easy to drink!
レポーターや！
A reporter!
ソムリエ？
Sommelier?
案件来てん？
Got a sponsored gig?
すごい
Amazing
え、これをさ、飲ませてくれた、ありがとね？
Eh, thanks for letting me drink this, y'know?
まだ終わりじゃない！
It's not over yet!
まだ終わりじゃないから！
Because it's not over yet!
まだあるの！？
There's more!?
まだ！まだあるんだよ！まだ前半戦なんだ！！
Still! There's still more! It's still just the first half!!
誰もルール聞いてなかったですけどｗ
Nobody listened to the rules w
はい、ここで！
Yes, right here!
宴会芸には持ってこいのゲームを用意しておりまーす！
We've prepared a game perfect for party tricks!
なんだー！？
What is it-!?
王様だーれだ！
Who is the king!
それ違う違う！
That's wrong, wrong!
それ違う！
That's wrong!
ツイスターゲーム！
Twister game!
ツイスターゲームのルールは 皆さんご存知ということで
As you all know the rules of the Twister game,
はい、はい。
yes, yes!
最初の対戦カードは、犬神ころね対雪花ラミィ。
The first matchup is Inugami Korone versus Yukihana Lamy.
ルールは、私、友人が、仕留めさせていただきます。
The rules will be enforced by yours truly, a friend.
いっ、焦らせんなよ！
Hey, don't rush me!
あ、今日の主役頑張ってください！
Ah, good luck to today's main character!
がんばって！
Do your best!
左足、緑にお願いします。
Left foot on green, please.
左足緑！
Left foot green!
あ、下から…良いです…おっ良いじゃん。
Ah, from underneath... good... Oh, very nice.
早い。張り切っております。
Fast. She's all fired up.
右足、赤で。
Right foot on red.
右足赤。はい、やった。
Right foot red. Okay, done.
よし、やった。こんな…
Alright, done. Like thi—
そんな余裕。
Such composure.
はい。じゃあ次行きます。
Alright. Now for the next one.
右手、黄色。いいですね。
Right hand on yellow. Nice.
おっ、いいんじゃない？ 余裕そうですよ？
Oh, isn't that good? Looks like a breeze, huh?
お、なんと、ころねさんも右手黄色で。
Oh, and Korone-san's right hand is also on yellow.
同じ！
Same!
おっ、おっ、余裕では？ 余裕じゃん！
Oh, oh! Isn't that easy? Totally easy!
全然。まあ、いまんところ大丈夫そうですね。健闘。
Not at all. Well, looks fine for now. Good fight.
え、いいの？ 違うとこね。
Eh, is that okay? Somewhere else, then.
ころねの右手、あほです。
Korone's right hand... is an idiot.
なんか落ち着いてるな…。落ち着いてるよ。
She's acting so calm... She's calm.
あっ、ちょっとハプニングのマスに手をつけてしまいましたがい、
Ah, she accidentally put her hand on the happening square, but
右手を黄色い円に置いて、ダジャレを言ってくださいw
please place your right hand on a yellow circle and tell a pun lol.
うわああああ！そういうこともあるの！？
Whoaa! Things like that happen too!?
え、ダジャレ？「あらヨット」さんですかからね。
Eh, a pun? Because it's "Ara-Yacht"-san.
誰だ！ 今「あらヨット」つったの！
Who was that! Who just said "Ara-Yacht"!
ヨット…。なんだっけ？ もう忘れちゃったよ…。
Yacht... What was it? I already forgot...
ダジャレを言うのは誰じゃ！！ すんません！！
Who's the one telling puns!! I'm sorry!!
10秒間大きな声で叫んでください！
Scream at the top of your lungs for 10 seconds!
お酒みや！
Sake-miya!
ころずら。なんか変わんない。
Koro-zura. Doesn't really change.
左足青。
Left foot blue.
なんかこうやってハプニングを…。あ、そうやって、あ、なるほど。
Like this, handling the happening... Ah, like that, ah, I see.
あ、おちりが！あ、見えちゃった！
Ah, her butt! Ah, it can be seen!
これはおい。見るな！
Hey, this is— Don't look!
見るな！
Don't look!
ながそで。いてててて、げろげろ。ん？
Long sleeves. Ouch ouch ouch, barf barf. Hm?
お願いします。あ、なんか。
Please. Ah, somehow.
記念撮影撮ってんの？
Are you taking a commemorative photo?
せーの、お尻が。あ、いいです。
Ready, go. Her butt is— Ah, good.
左手を緑の円に置いて、隣のプレイヤーとじゃんけんをしてくだ…
Place your left hand on a green circle and play rock-paper-scissors with the adjacent player...
え、そういうこと？
Eh, like that?
じゃ～んけ～ん、ぽん！
Rock-paper-scissors, pon!
勝ったけど？ 負けたけど？ 終わりですw
I won though? I lost though? It's over lol.
じゃあ特に何かある訳ではない。
So there isn't really anything special.
右手を黄色い円に置いて、好きな果物を言ってください。
Place your right hand on a yellow circle and say your favorite fruit.
え？ バナナ。
Eh? Banana.
右手上げてくださーい。キープで。
Raise your right hand, please. Keep it there.
そうだ、二人ともなんか無難な位置に置くからさ、相手がさ、行けないような位置に戦略的にいこう。
That's right, both of you place it in safe spots, so strategically let's place it where the opponent can't reach.
次が、右手赤でお願いします。
Next is, right hand on red, please.
右手赤？ 妨害、妨害！
Right hand red? Interference, interference!
新奇なほら、赤。あ！
Look at this novelty, red. Ah!
これもう動けないよ！？
You can't move anymore like this?!
これ危なくない！？
Isn't this dangerous?!
同じとこには置けません！！
You cannot place it in the same spot!!
おいダメ。あっ、めっちゃ遠くにで、で、こっちしかない…！
Hey, no. Ah, way over there, and, and, only this way left...!
無理っ！無理い～！
Impossible! No wayyy!
これは詰んだんじゃね？ ああ、これはだめか。
Isn't this checkmate? Ah, guess this is no good.
雪花ラミィ OUT！
Yukihana Lamy OUT!
まさかの泥酔のころねが、こんなになるとは思わなかった。
Never expected that a completely drunk Korone would end up like this.
いや、基礎体力違いますからね。
Well, base physical strength is different, after all.
第二回戦もありますからね！
There's also a second round, you know!
続いては、白金ノエル、宝鐘マリン、白衣こよみの水の間大乱戦の予感。
Next up, a feeling of a massive three-way battle between Shiranui Noel, Houshou Marine, and Hakui Koyori.
左足黄色。左足黄色。
Left foot yellow. Left foot yellow.
はい、とりあえず冷静にね。まず一歩冷静に一歩踏み出して。
Okay, first stay calm. First, calmly take a step forward.
おお、長袖ですね。
Oh, long sleeves, huh.
右手、黄色。
Right hand, yellow.
さすがに。あれ？ノエルなんか…。
As expected. Huh? Noel, somehow...
股が！！！ こめんこめんw 気をつけて…！
Her crotch is!!! Sorry sorry lol. Be careful...!
まだ何もしてないのに勝手に開き出した。
She started opening up on her own even though she hadn't done anything yet.
右手赤。ノエルの邪魔になる場所にしようよ。
Right hand red. Let's put it somewhere that gets in Noel's way.
行く。ここ。あ、いいね、いいね。
Going. Here. Ah, nice, nice.
まだこよりが絡んでないじゃん。
Koyori hasn't gotten tangled yet, huh.
左手赤。あ、じゃあここかな？
Left hand red. Ah, then how about here?
これこれ！見たかったやつぅ！！
This is it! This is what I wanted to see!!
その体勢キツイだろ、大丈夫か？w
That posture must be tough, are you alright? lol
やばい！デュワアアアア！
Oh no! Gwaaaaa!
ああ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
右足赤。赤？赤！？あー！
Right foot red. Red? Red!? Aah!
キツそう。これやばい。ヤバイヤバイ、近いですね。
Looks tough. This is bad. Oh no oh no, it's close.
すごいな、知恵の輪みたいになってる。
Amazing, it's like a Chinese puzzle.
左足浮かしてください。
Float your left foot, please.
左足浮かす！？
Float my left foot!?
いつまで！？ ずっとですぅ！！
Until when!? Forever!!
なんじゃこれ。左手緑でお願いします。
What on earth is this. Left hand on green, please.
なんじゃこりゃ！デュワアアアアアアアアア！
What is this! Gwaaaaaaaaaaa!
こよりの手がぁ！！持っていかれたぁ～！！
Koyori's hand was taken away!!
マリンさん、右足、青。
Marine-san, right foot, blue.
え、左足はどうしたらいいの…？
Eh, what should I do with my left foot...?
浮かしたままでーす。
Keep it lifted.
浮かしたまま!? 片足でガタガタしてる
Lifted?! You're shaking on one leg!
はい。あ、やべ、お！あ、すごい！
Yes. Ah, yabe, oh! Ah, amazing!
すごい！すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing! Amazing!
宝鐘マリンOUT。セーフ！マリンさんセーフよ。
Houshou Marine OUT. Safe! Marine-san is safe.
いや、無理だろ！！
No, that's impossible!!
いや、無理だろ、ちょっと、これ。
No, that's impossible, seriously.
博衣こより、右手[赤]と出てしまいました。
Hakui Koyori, right hand [red] came up.
右手赤ね。
Right hand red, huh.
え、じゃあ、ここに行くしかないですね。
Eh, then I have no choice but to go here.
おお！絡んでるねぇ～！！絡んでる絡んでる、すりすり～♡
Ooh! You're tangling up!! Tangle, tangle, rub rub~♡
はい、そしたら、まあ、荒くなやつですね。あたたたたですね。
Right, so, well, a rough one. Atatatata.
あ、「ハプニングマス」が出ました。『耳フー』しますかね。
Ah, "Happening Space" appeared. Shall we do "Ear Blow"?
『耳フー』来ました！来ちゃったぁ～(喜)
"Ear Blow" came! It came~ (happy)
マリさん、やったれ！いくぞぉっ!!
Mari-san, go get 'em! Let's go!!
マリ！いや、こっちだ、こっち。
Mari! No, over here, over here.
じゃあ、マリンがちょっと…耳フーします。やめてw
Then Marine will... do the ear blow. Stop it lol.
耳フーします。逃げないで！逃げないで。いきます！いくぞぉっ!!
I'll do the ear blow. Don't run away! Don't run away. Here I go! Let's go!!
あぁー！地獄絵図。なんだこの絵面。
Aah! A scene from hell. What is this composition?
ころねさん余裕w ユゥ～w 可愛い、可愛い。
Korone-san is so relaxed lol. Yuyu~ lol. Cute, cute.
冷たいけど温かい♡ こよりの耳フーあたってるw
Cold yet warm♡ Koyori's ear blow is hitting right lol.
どうですか二人とも。「冷たいけど温かい」って何w 今の気分はどうですか？
How is it, you two? What does "cold yet warm" even mean lol. How are you feeling right now?
気分は最悪です。最悪なの？
My mood is the worst. The worst?
こんな、こんななの？
Is it really that bad?
こよりは最高でしたよ♪ おかしいな、格差社会が。
Koyori was amazing♪ That's strange, a society of inequality.
右足、緑。いや、無理じゃない？
Right foot, green. No, isn't that impossible?
いや、無理じゃない？前をずっと…アクロバティックノエル！
No, isn't that impossible? Moving forward the whole time... Acrobatic Noel!
左足、緑。左足緑。あ、ちょうど。あ、でも、まだいけます。あ、まだ大丈夫だね。
Left foot, green. Left foot green. Ah, perfect. Ah, but we can still go. Ah, it's still fine.
こより、右足が自由なんですよね、実は。あ、そうなんですね！結構いける。
Koyori, your right foot is actually free, right? Ah, is that so! You can do quite a bit.
ノエルさん…w 笑うな、笑うな。ノエルさんと、右手、赤。
Noel-san... lol Don't laugh, don't laugh. Noel-san and right hand, red.
ええ！？右手赤。さすがいにもう無理か？
Eh?! Right hand red. Surely you can't do this anymore?
白銀ノエルOUT！
Shirogane Noel OUT!
やったぁー！勝ちました！
Yay~! I won!
博衣こよりWIN！やったぁー！
Hakui Koyori WIN! Yay~!
やり切ったノエルさんの顔。顔やばい。あ、最悪。
Noel-san's face after giving it her all. Her face is terrible. Ah, the worst.
こよちゃんもありがと～！こちらこそ～！
Koyo-chan, thank you too~! Likewise~!
楽しかったで～す！いい戦いでした！
It was fun~! It was a good match!
ありがとうございます！ありがとうございました！この後も誕生日楽しんでくださ～い！
Thank you very much! Thank you! Please continue enjoying the birthday stream~!
はい、続いては、違うお酒と新たなゲストが待っているので、一旦、お口直しで録画済みのLIVEをご覧ください～！
Yes, up next, different drinks and new guests await, so please enjoy a pre-recorded LIVE performance as a palate cleanser~!
高次元的恋がわかんない
I don't understand high-dimensional love
好きって気持ちもわかんない
I don't understand the feeling of love either
凡骨の計算も解けない
I can't even solve an ordinary person's calculations
霊長類の正体が怪しい
The true identity of primates is suspicious
感じ合って　間違って　叶わない　この気持ちは何なんだろう
Feeling each other, making mistakes, unfulfilled—what is this feeling?
現象 It's maybe yo　転生妄想は招待制にして
Phenomenon, it's maybe yo. Let's make reincarnation delusions by invitation only.
チューリングラブ見つめ合ったって　届かない距離ならワンピ－ス
Turing Love, even if we gaze at each other, if it's an unreachable distance, it's a One Piece.
ラッキー牧場　1・2・3で　明かす速さ
Lucky ranch, revealing at the speed of 1, 2, 3.
僕まで生み出す現象　ハート型奏でるアンサー
A phenomenon that even creates me, an answer playing in the shape of a heart.
信じたくたって信じないけど　証明しよう　今度はABC
Even if I want to believe, I won't. Let's prove it this time with ABC.
好きを教えておくれよ　思考回路サスペンス映画
Teach me what love is, a suspense film of thought circuits.
予測不可能性のフリをして見ろ　さあ証明しよう　証明しよう
Try pretending to have unpredictability, come on, let's prove it, let's prove it.
世界があるなら証明しよう　証明しよう　神聖なチューリングラブ
If the world exists, let's prove it, let's prove it. A sacred Turing Love.
どうぞ証明したい　正反対に見えない？　無理なんだよ　ESSAY
Please, I want to prove it. Don't we look opposite? It's impossible, ESSAY.
導き出したい　辿り着きたい　最適解は？　何度から回ったってぶつかっちゃって
I want to derive it, I want to reach it. What is the optimal solution? No matter how many times we spin around and collide,
不思議なこのアノマリーを解き明かす過程さ　必要条件です
it's the process of unraveling this mysterious anomaly; it's a necessary condition.
あー、恋の定義がわからない
Ah, I don't know the definition of love,
まずスキって基準もわからない
nor do I know the baseline for kissing.
要は、恋してるときが恋らしい
The point is, loving moments are lovely!
客観? 主観? エビデンススプリー!
Objective? Subjective? Evidence Spree!
愛は計算じゃ解けない
Love cannot be solved by calculations,
まず普通の計算も解けない
in fact, normal math can't be solved either.
要は、そんな状態が愛らしい
The point is, such states are lovely.
もう大抵的事象において Q があって A を出して解けるのに
Most phenomena have a Q and an A to solve them,
勘違いして間違って 解のないこの気持ちはなんだろう
but this inexplicable feeling is what?
DAZING!! モーションは相対性にステイ
DAZING!! Motion stays relative.
チューリングラブ 見つめあったって解けないメロウ
Turing Love: Melody that can't be solved by staring.
ワッツアップラブ いま 123 で証そうか
What's Up Love: Let's prove it with 1-2-3 now.
言葉で生み出すクエスチョン (クエスチョン!)
A question born from words (Question!)
ハートで高鳴るアンサー (アンサー!)
An answer echoing in the heart (Answer!)
測ったって不確定性 ぼくらの BPM
Measured uncertainty, our BPM.
チューリングラブ 穹に舞ったって信じないけど
Turing Love: Hard to believe we danced in the sky,
フォーリングラブ いまは ABC すらバグそうだな
Falling Love: Even ABCs might bug out now.
なんでか教えてオイラー (オイラー!)
Teach me why, oh Euler (Euler!)
感想きかせてフェルマー (フェルマー!)
Let me hear your thoughts, felmer (Felmer!)
予測不可能性 いま触れてみる
Unpredictable, let's touch it now.
さあ証明しよう (証明しよう) 間違いのないように
Come on, let's prove it (Let's prove it), without a single mistake,
証明しよう (証明しよう) この感情全部全部
let's prove it (Let's prove it), all of this emotion,
証明しよう (証明しよう) 正解があるなら
let's prove it (Let's prove it), if there is a correct answer,
証明しよう (証明しよう) シンプルな Q.E.D.
let's prove it (Let's prove it), with a simple Q.E.D.
今日こそ証明したい! (したい!)
I want to prove it today! (Prove it!)
目に見えない 無理難題を ASAP!
Invisible, impossible problems ASAP!
導き出したい たどり着きたい 最適解へ
I want to derive and reach the optimal solution.
「三次元空間(立体)における二点 AB間の距離を求めよ」的な感じだと思ってたのに
Thinking we were tasked to find the distance AB
座標も公式も見当たらないし
coordinates and formulas are nowhere to be found,
参考資料にも載っていないから
nor are they in the reference materials,
きみと生み出して見せてみたいじゃん
so I want to create them with you.
三次元空間(世界)における この気持ちの求め方
How to find this feeling in a three-dimensional space (world),
丸だってバツだって 不安にとってイクールで
circle means a cross, insecurely echoing,
近づかなくなって遠くなって 揺れるこの気持ちのハリも
getting closer, getting farther, the tension of this shaking feeling.
ステップインモーションは相対性ミステイク
Step in, motion is relative, mistake.
チューリングラブ 騒ぎ出した 胸の痛くなるほど
Turing Love: Busting out, making my heart ache.
とある言葉がきみに突き刺さり
A certain word pierced deeply into you,
傷口から漏れ出す液を“愛”と形容してみたの
and I tried describing the fluid leaking from the wound as "love."
思いやりのおとぎと形だけの交尾は
An intersection of missing pieces and mere shapes
腐れ縁のきみとあたしによく似ている
is very similar to you and me in our rotten fate.
それでも「好き」とか
Even so, can we say "I like you"
愛したっていいじゃないか
or "I loved you"?
縛り 誰も触れないように
Binding us so no one else can touch—
これも運命じゃないか
isn't this also destiny?
消える消える とある愛世
Fading, fading, a certain world of love;
終わる頃にはきみに飽きているよ
by the time it ends, I'll be tired of you.
愛か欲か分からず放つことは何としようか
Not knowing whether to love or want, what should we call letting go?
思いやりのおとぎと形だけの交尾は
An intersection of missing pieces and mere shapes
腐れ縁のきみとあたしによく似ている
is very similar to you and me in our rotten fate.
それでもいいから…
Even so, is it okay to say...
愛したっていうのですか?
"I loved you"?
しがみついて苔むすことを
Clinging on and picking at the moss.
殺したっていいじゃないか
Is it okay to say "I killed you"
きみが嫌うあたしなんて
about this me that you hate?
愛したっていいじゃないか
Is it okay to say "I loved you"?
縛り 誰も触れないように
Binding us so no one else can touch—
これも運命じゃないか
isn't this also destiny?
消える消える とある愛せ
Fading, fading, a certain eternal love.
闇の中にはきみに抗いて いるよ
Even in this darkness, I am here, defying you.
愛か良くか
Whether you love me or not,
分からず放つことは 何としよう
what should we do about things we can't speak of?
思いやりの欠如と形だけの媚びは
An intersection of missing pieces and mere shapes
腐れ縁のきみとあたしによく似ている
is very similar to you and me in our rotten fate.
それでもいいから
Even so, that's fine too.
愛したいから
I want to love you!
愛したっていうのですぐ
"I loved you," you say,
しがみついてもがくことを
yet you cling on and try to kill me.
殺したっていいじゃないか
"I could kill you," I say,
きみが嫌うあたしなんて
when you hate a person like me.
愛したっていいじゃないか
"I loved you," you say.
縛り 誰も触れないよう
Binding us so no one else can touch—
これも運命じゃないか
isn't this also destiny?
消える消える とある愛せ
Fading, fading, a certain eternal love.
はい、というわけでね。
So, with that said,
続いてのゲストは…ライブでもわかったと思いますが！
Our next guest... as you probably know from the live!
この方！
This person!
お邪魔しまーす！
Coming in!
鷹嶺ルイ、おめでとうございまーす！
Takane Lui! Congratulations!
酒臭えな、なんか。
It smells like booze in here...
何飲んでたんですかぁ？日本酒飲んでましたぁ～
What were you drinking? We were drinking sake~
酔っ払ってます？大丈夫ですか？
Are you drunk? Are you okay?
大丈夫、大丈夫。私お邪魔して大丈夫です！
We're fine, fine. Is it okay if I intrude?
お邪魔しまーす。…てことでね。
Excuse me. ...So, anyway,
ルイ姉といえば？ 私はワインが大好きです。
Speaking of Lui-nee? I love wine.
ワイン！
Wine!
え、ワイン用意してくれてるんですか？
Eh, did you prepare wine for us?
そうなんです。ねえ、飲めるの？
That's right. Hey, can we drink it?
最初のワインは何やら貴腐のオーラを放っていますね。
The first wine gives off some kind of noble rot aura.
貴腐ワイン、でございます。
It's noble rot wine.
貴腐ワインとは、原料の葡萄に貴腐菌（ボトリティス・シネレア）がついて育った葡萄を使用したワイン。
Noble rot wine is wine made from grapes grown with noble rot fungus.
わぁ、すっげえ！なんて上品な…
Wow, amazing! How elegant...
付着すると、あの葡萄の果汁から水分が蒸発し、干し葡萄のようになるので糖分が凝縮されます。
When attached, moisture evaporates from the grape juice, becoming like raisins so sugar is concentrated.
一般的な葡萄の糖度が20～24度にに対して60度を超えるものもあります。
While normal grapes have a sugar content of 20-24 degrees, some exceed 60 degrees.
そう、貴腐ワインは甘口で有名なですね、蜂蜜のように甘美で芳醇な味わいだそうです。
Yes, noble rot wine is famous for being sweet, with a honey-like, luscious, and mellow taste.
お値段は5万5000円となっております。
The price is 55,000 yen.
それでは55飲んでいただきましょう！
Let's have everyone drink '55'!
じゃあ私が注ぎましょうかね？
Shall I pour it?
かんぱーい！！
Cheers!!
あまーーい…！！あまっ！！
So sweeet...! Sweet!!
おいしい～！むせ返るくらい甘い！
Delicious~! Sweet enough to make you choke!
今まで飲んだワイン…ワインで一番甘いかもしれない。
The wine I've ever drunk... might be the sweetest wine.
アイスにかけて食べたい…！
I want to pour it over ice cream...!
飲めちゃうわぁ。
I could just drink it up.
蜜みたいです、本当に。カブトムシの気分…
It's really like honey. I feel like a rhinoceros beetle...
カブトムシこんな良いもん飲んでないよ！
Rhinoceros beetles don't drink anything this good!
もう1本、ワインをご用意してありまーす！
We have another bottle of wine prepared!
海底で造るやつ！！すごい有名なやつだ！！
The one made at the bottom of the sea!! That's super famous!!
深度60メートルの水圧と内部ガス圧を利用し熟成時のストレスをなくして造られたワイン。
A wine aged at a depth of 60m using water pressure and internal gas pressure to eliminate aging stress.
なんかガサガサしてるよ…？
It feels kind of rough...?
あえて海に沈めるの？すごいね。
You dare sink it in the ocean? That's amazing.
これが味だって言ってんのに他の三人が『汚な～』みたいな感じでね。『洗ったら？』
Even though they said this is the taste, the other three were like 'Gross~'... 'Wash it?'
お値段は3万3000円となっております。
The price is 33,000 yen.
なんか海の匂いはするような気がする…ような気がする。
It kind of feels like it smells like the ocean... or maybe not.
しないだろ！
No it doesn't!
かんぱーい！
Cheers!
意外と炭酸強い！！シュワシュワしてるぅ！！
It's surprisingly carbonated!! It's fizzy!!
お酒感なくないですか？全然違うよこれ！
Doesn't it lack alcohol feel? This is totally different!
すごい口当たりがシュワシュワする…！
The mouthfeel is super fizzy...!
ちょっと辛口…？
A bit dry...?
ではないですよね。
Not really.
皆さんなんか食べたかったりしませんか？
Doesn't everyone want to eat something?
ワインコーナーにもおつまみを用意しております！
We also have snacks prepared in the wine corner!
44ヶ月熟成（ほぼ4年）！
Aged for 44 months (almost 4 years)!
でお値段約15万円！
And the price is about 150,000 yen!
ちょっと生ハムの方が高いんですけど大きさを見て頂きたいわ
The jamón serrano is pricier, but I want you to see the size!
おわぁぁぁぁぁぁ!!
Whoa!
でっけぇ!!
That's huge!
バットやん!
It's like a bat!
10kgあるそうですよ
Apparently, it weighs 10 kilograms.
皆さんの元にはねちょっと切った物をお出ししております
We've prepared some pre-sliced portions for you all.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
私にも出して頂いてる!! ありがた～い!
You prepared some for me too?! So grateful!
食べちゃうよぉ？いいですか？
We're gonna eat it, okay? Is that alright?
すっごいしょっぱい…しょっぱい肉
It's super salty... Such a salty meat.
日本酒とも合うな
But it goes great with sake.
嫌味のない塩辛さって感じ
It has a clean, pleasant saltiness.
あ、そんな感じ嫌味のない塩 同じだね言ってること 一言一句いっしょw
Ah, a clean, pleasant saltiness... We're saying the exact same thing word for word! LOL
え、なんかすごい、うわ、しょっぱさだけじゃなくて、なんか丁寧な味しませんなんか
It's not just salty, it has this refined flavor to it, you know?
なんかおしゃれなお店にある粗塩みたいな味がする
It tastes like coarse salt you'd find at a fancy restaurant.
岩塩みたいなね、岩塩のさ、なんかそれだけなめても全然味があるみたいな感じだよね
Like rock salt, where even if you just lick it by itself, it has so much flavor.
外側の黄色い所は削いじゃうの？これ
Do you shave off the yellow outer part?
原木…あ、削いじゃうみたいですよ！中身削るみたいですけどね
Ah, you apparently shave it off! Shave down to the inner meat, it seems.
シェフが頷いている
The chef is nodding.
骨になるまで削っていくってこと？
You keep shaving it down until it's just bone?
これさ、あらかじめ、生まれつきしょっぱいの？
Is this... inherently salty from birth?
生ハムの原木に塩をって言われて、多分塩、塩とかを食べさせるんじゃない？
They tell you to put salt on jamón serrano, so maybe they feed them salt or something?
え、なわけないよぉ！！
No way, that can't be right!
うちのスタッフ…今すぐ何かを言いそうな顔してるわ
Our staff... look like they want to say something right now.
キャビアだ！
Caviar!
すげぇ高級なの入ってる！嘘でしょ!? キャビアです！ すげぇ！
Wow, this is super high-end! No way! It's caviar! Amazing!
キャビアってどんな味がするの？
What does caviar taste like anyway?
魚介、魚介の…卵やない？
Seafood... Seafood eggs, right?
キャビアつけて…え、食べいただけます
You eat it with crackers... Please go ahead and try it.
なんかキャビアの味なのか何なのかわかんないけど今キャビアの味がするっ！
I don't know if this is what caviar tastes like or what, but I taste caviar right now!
多分それがキャビアなんだわ！ これがキャビアだ！
That must be what caviar is! This is caviar!
すごいコクがありますね、このキャビア
It has incredible depth of flavor, this caviar.
でもこれは貴腐ワインと合いますね、このキャビア
But this pairs really well with noble rot wine, this caviar.
100万円分食べて頂きましたよこれで！ あー美味しい！
You've eaten 1 million yen worth with this! Ah, so delicious!
え、いいのこれ？だって食べてるだけだよさっきから。このままで良いんか？
Wait, is this really okay? We've just been eating the whole time. Is this fine as is?
いや、でもね、フリートークでいいかとは思いますけれども、ちょっとゲームをね…
Well, free talk is fine and all, but we should do a little game...
このまま帰っちゃいけないんだわ！このまま帰らない！ですよ？
We can't just go home like this! We're not letting you leave just yet!
さっきゲームやったんだから、ま、ここでもゲームやりますよ！なるほどね、ゲームあったんですね
Since we played a game earlier, we're playing a game here too! Ah, I see, there is a game.
そういう流れで行きましょうか！じゃあちょっと場面を…
Let's go with that flow! Alright, let's transition the scene...
椅子取りゲーム！いや、やってきてしまいましたこの悪のようなゲーム…
Musical Chairs! Ah, we've arrived at this demonic game...
悪魔なの？なんで？はい、まぁ、椅子取りゲームは…
Demonic? Why? Well, musical chairs is...
いいんですよ、分かりますよね？もうみんなで蹴落として頂いて、自分が座るという、音楽が止まりましたら…
It's fine, you know how it goes, right? You just knock each other down and take a seat when the music stops...
ケツで押し出しOKですか？
Is pushing with our butts allowed?
まあまあまあちょっと親しきね、100万円分のね、あの、お酒たちを飲んだ皆さんですから、100万円のこう座りをちゃんと優雅にね、いただいて…ケツで押し出しは…NGですね、それは。
Well, you guys drank 1 million yen worth of alcohol, so let's have a graceful 1 million yen sitting experience... Pushing with butts is... NG, absolutely not.
あ、ケツで押し出すとちょっとマリンさん勝っちゃうんでね。手の押し出しも、尻の押し出しもだめですよ！
Ah, if we allow butt pushes, Marine-san might win. No pushing with hands or butts!
ただ皆さんにはあの、押し出されちゃった方は、あの、1枚ずつ脱いでいただこうかなと…あら！
However, whoever gets pushed out will have to strip off one layer of clothing... Oh my!
ええと、誕生日めの人からの希望ですけど、何ですか？あのノエル先輩の、キャストオフが見たいです
Um, this is a request from the birthday girl, but what is it? She wants to see Noel-senpai's cast-off!
脱めようぜぇー!! 脱ぎなさい！ 今まで隠してたんでしょ？見せてください。
Let's strip her down! Strip! You've been hiding it all this time, haven't you? Show us.
椅子取りゲーム、マジで強いからね！で、４人が敵だよ！
I'm really good at musical chairs! And the four of you are my enemies!
急に悪質なゲームになりましたけれども、じゃあ行きますか！
This suddenly turned into a malicious game, but shall we begin?
はい、それではミュージックスタート！
Alright, then, music start!
この夏は何度も夢見た潮騒の宝物
How many times this summer did we dream of the shore's treasure?
shiny smile smile your heart heart to heart oh yeah
（せーのっ）ぴえんぱおんはおにゆんお待たせっ ♡
(Ready, set) Pien paon oh niyun, keep you waiting ♡
さーまっさーまっさーまっ あっちっちーのさーまっ
Summer, summer, summer, scorching summer!
戌神ころね OUT！
Inugami Korone is OUT!
えーちゃん!!えーちゃんやん！あ、審議入りますか？w
E-chan! It's E-chan! Wait, are we calling for a review? LOL
審議入りますか？リプレイw
Should we review it? Replay! LOL
私の横で座ってたころさんが何故か椅子がなくなっていたw お尻押してましたねなんか
Korone-san was sitting right next to me, but somehow her chair disappeared! She was pushing with her butt.
ノエルちゃんハメようって言ってたじゃん(泣)だって横にいたんだもんw
You said let's frame Noel-chan! (Crying) But she was right next to me! LOL
座ってきたからさ、このケツでか～w スポーツマンシップも何もないゲーム
She sat down on me, so with that huge butt~ LOL A game with zero sportsmanship whatsoever.
戌神ころね 一枚脱衣！
Inugami Korone, strip off one layer!
ころちゃん
Koro-chan.
着替えられましたか〜？
Have you finished changing?
どうですか？
How is it?
はい…
Yes...
あ、かわいい！
Ah, so cute!
あ、でもだね
Ah, but you know,
チャックが残ってますからw
there's still a zipper left onｗ
あ、本当だ！
Ah, true!
え、でもなんか可愛いですよね。新鮮じゃないですか？
Eh, but it's kind of cute. Isn't it fresh?
あれ、ころね…そんなにおっぱいおっきかったかなあ…
Wait, Korone... were her breasts always that big...
やめなさい！！！
Stop that!!!
はい、こういう魔のゲームでございますので、皆さん頑張って生き残ってください。特にマリンさん危ないので
Yes, since this is a demonic game, everyone please do your best to survive. Especially Marine-san, you're in danger, so—
ちょっとちょっと！
Wait, wait!
ころね！
Korone!
ノエルとはね、公園でデートしてケツで押し出したこともあるから
Noel and I once went on a date in the park and I pushed her out with my butt,
公園のベンチで…
on a park bench...
はい、じゃあ行きますよ。
Alright, let's go.
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
同じ未来を見 て い たい
We want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
we want to hold that dream in our hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with our respective hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
In a pitch-dark place wherever we looked, it sprouted.
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
This gaze was stolen by just a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning our anxiously shaking hearts skillfully,
ほんの小さな勇気を振り絞っていたよ
we mustered up just a tiny bit of courage.
白銀ノエル OUT！
Shirogane Noel is OUT!
イエーイ！
Yay!
白銀ノエル、一枚脱衣
Shirogane Noel strips off one layer of clothing.
途中ですごい格好で止まったの、誰ですか？w
Who stopped in such an amazing pose midway?w
これじゃ、ほら！
Look at this, see!
はやい！はずかしい！
So fast! How embarrassing!
あらあら…
Oh my...
いや、これちょっとラミィのチャンネルが危ぶまれる
Man, Lamy's channel might be in jeopardy.
どんといこい！
Bring it on!
いやちょっと露出度あがってきたなあ、肌が増えてきました
Man, the exposure level has gone up, more skin is showing.
歌ってるとね、止まってるのか聞こえなくてw 一回無音にしてみよう！
When singing, you can't hear if you stopped or notw Let's try making it silent once!
同じ未来を見 て い たい
We want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
we want to hold that dream in our hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with our respective hearts, go!
どこを見ても真っ暗な場所に芽生えてた
In a pitch-dark place wherever we looked, it sprouted.
ほんの小さな希望にこの瞳奪われた
This gaze was stolen by just a tiny hope.
不安で揺れる心をうまくチューニングして
Tuning our anxiously shaking hearts skillfully,
宝鐘マリン OUT！
Houshou Marine is OUT!
めちゃめちゃダサい落ち方しちゃったけどマリンさん
She fell in such a super uncool way, Marine-san.
果てしなくダサい落ち方
Such an endlessly uncool way of falling.
ラミィさんのチャンネルでダサい落ち方でしたねw
Such an uncool way to fall on Lamy's channelw
宝鐘マリン、一枚脱衣
Houshou Marine strips off one layer of clothing.
でもころねが次負けたら…ころねの恨みを感じた
But if Korone loses next... I felt Korone's grudge.
もう悔しくかないよもう！
I'm not even frustrated anymore!
やだあ〜！！
No way~~!!
帰ってきましたか？
Have you returned?
さっきと一緒だよ
It's the same as before.
何が恥ずかしいんじゃ
What's so embarrassing about it?
ここ入って
Get in here.
ころねじゃあ行きますよ
Alright Korone, here we go.
同じ未来を見 て い たい
We want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
we want to hold that dream in our hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with our respective hearts, go!
なんかすごい仲良し？仲良しなの？
Are you guys super close? Are you close friends?
雪花ラミィ OUT！
Yukihana Lamy is OUT!
これはちょっとね
This is a bit...
可愛く座っちゃいましたけどw
She sat down so cute thoughw
雪花ラミィ、一枚脱衣
Yukihana Lamy strips off one layer of clothing.
恥ずかしいよっ！
How embarrassing!
あ、恥ずかしい…はずかしい…
Ah, embarrassing... so embarrassing...
芝居やなw
What an actw
お疲れ様です
Good work.
これでみんな脱ぎ…あれっ！？
With this everyone is nudgi... Wait!?
ルイさん！！
Lui-san!!
ちょっとちょっと！
Wait, wait!
脱げよ！脱げよ！
Strip! Strip!
このまま空気を読かずに圧勝したい
I want to win overwhelmingly without reading the room.
やめてやめてw
Stop it, stop itw
圧勝したいと思います〜！
I want to win overwhelmingly~!
同じ未来を見 て い たい
We want to see the same future,
あの夢手にしたい
we want to hold that dream in our hands.
それぞれ違ったココロで走れ go
Run with our respective hearts, go!
鷹嶺ルイ OUT！
Takane Lui is OUT!
待て待て、足が…
Wait, wait, my legs...
あんなにいきってたのに、直後すぎるだろw
Even though she was acting so cocky, that was way too soonw
ガチで負けた…w
I seriously lost...w
来るかね？
Are they coming?
来たかね？
Did they come?
恥ずかしい...
Embarrassing...
なんも変わってないじゃん
Nothing's changed at all!
なんも露出してないだろ、そんなの！
You're not exposing anything at all!
出すぎ！
Too much!
それでは皆さん、心構えはいいですか？
Are you all prepared?
はーい！
Yes!
ミュージック、スタート！
Music, start!
先輩の足に負けるな！
Don't lose to senpai's feet!
可愛く可愛くいきましょう！
Let's go cute and adorable!
はい、に、さん、はい！
One, two, three, go!
おらあっ！！
Take that!
あれ？
Huh?
おらあっ！！
Take that!
白銀ノエル、OUT！
Shirogane Noel, OUT!
ケツ圧に負けたんだけどw
I lost to the butt pressure lol
今のはケツ圧やろ！！
That was totally butt pressure!
今実はマリン先輩、間に座ってましたから
Actually, Marine-senpai was sitting in between
あいだに！！座ってました！！
In between!! She was sitting there!!
もしかしてこれって…アウトですか？
Could this be... out?
2アウトです、宝鐘マリン OUT！
2 outs, Houshou Marine OUT!
ノエルさっきは無理やり押し出したりしてごめんね？
Noel, sorry for forcing you out earlier?
団長もちょっと怒り過ぎちゃってごめんね？
Commander, sorry for getting too mad too?
ふざけんなお前！
Are you kidding me!
おらおらおらおら！
Take that, take that!
ケンカだめですよ、一応ね！
No fighting, you know!
ダメでしょケンカしたら！
You shouldn't fight!
仲直りの…ほら、仲直りのぎゅーして？
As a make-up... hey, give a make-up hug?
ぎゅー ぎゅー
Hug, hug
なんだこれ？
What is this?
てぇてぇだな、なんだこれ？
So wholesome, what is this?
終わり？エンディングとなりますね！
Is it over? It's the ending!
終わりなの！？
It's already over!?
リスナーさんはさ、みんなが水着になる事を望んでるんだ
Listeners, you know, want everyone to be in swimwear
どうなんですか？
How is it?
せんぱーい！
Senpai!
ノエル二人きりになっちゃったね…ラミィの部屋でさ、こんな冬にさ、水着なんて…
Noel, we ended up alone... in Lamy's room, in this winter, wearing swimwear...
なんか友達の家でさ、こうやってさ、なんかいかがわしい格好でさ… やめてえええええ！！
Like at a friend's house, dressed all lewdly like this... Stop ittttt!!
ずっと見てたかったのに！変な感じにするのやめて！！
I wanted to keep watching! Stop making it weird!!
ラミィのお誕生日に来てくれてありがとーー！！
Thank you for coming to Lamy's birthday!!
おめでとー！！ありがとうございます！！
Happy birthday!! Thank you very much!!
このあとグッズの告知もあるのでよろしくお願いしますまーす！
There will be merch announcements after this, so please look forward to it!
それではそれぞれサービスショットで！
Now, everyone with their service shots!
え、サービスショット？
Eh, service shot?
サービスどこサービス！？ダメダメダメ！
Service where service!? No no no!
はい終わりです！！バイバーイ！ありがとうございましたー！！
Yes, it's over!! Bye-bye!! Thank you very much!!
ということで、雪花ラミィ誕生日記念2022 11月15日発売開始となっております！
So, Yukihana Lamy Birthday Commemoration 2022 goes on sale November 15th!
今回はですね、誕生日の記念フルセットは記念ボイス1種、記念グッズ3種となっております！
This time, the birthday commemoration full set includes 1 voice pack and 3 merchandise items!
まずは両面ブランケット！100万人記念のときの水族館の記念イラストなども担当してくださったホング先生に描き下ろしていただきました！
First is the double-sided blanket! Illustrated by Hong-sensei, who also did the aquarium anniversary art for the 1 million subscriber milestone!
しかもなんとなんと、フロントとバックで柄が違います！好きなほうをオモテにして使ってね！
And what's more, the front and back patterns are different! Use your favorite side facing front!
そして今回のブランケットなんとなんと、サイズがちょっと大きめになっています！横幅が140cm、縦が100cm！
And this blanket, believe it or not, is a bit larger in size! 140cm wide and 100cm tall!
一人で使うのはもちろん、二人で一緒に被ってもあったかくていいかもね！
Using it alone is great, but sharing it with two people might be nice and warm too!
そして次は、三連結アクリルキーホルダー！みたらしねこ先生に描いていただきました！みんなが好きな順番に連結して使ってね！
Next is the triple-connected acrylic keychain! Illustrated by Mitarashi Neko-sensei. Connect them in your favorite order!
そして、お待たせに、ついにでてきてしまいました！やめなーダイカットクッション！こちらフロントがノーマルやめな、裏がポルカ版のやめなになっています！
And finally, it's finally here! The "Yamena" die-cut cushion! Front is normal Yamena, back is Polka version Yamena!
用途はいろいろ！ふわふわしてる生地なので、枕にしたり抱きしめたりクッションにしたりいろんな用途があるけれども、いじめるのはやめな！かわいがってあげてください！
Various uses! Fluffy fabric, so pillow, hugging, cushion, lots of uses, but don't bully it! Please treat it with love!
そして最後に、シチュエーションボイス「暖かい誕生日とその先へ」。こちらね、今回のグッズも含めたシチュエーションボイスになっているのでぜひぜひブランケットとかね、用意して...
And finally, the situational voice "Warm Birthday and Beyond". This includes the merch in the scenario, so please prepare the blanket and...
聞いてもらえるととってもいいと思います！
I think it'd be wonderful if you listened to it!
そしてフルセット購入特典は
And the full set purchase bonus
ホング先生描き下ろしポストカードにラミィの複製サインとメッセージを入れて
is a postcard illustrated by Fuzichoco-sensei featuring Lamy's duplicated signature and message,
皆様にお届けいたします！
delivered straight to you!
さらに特典ボイス「誕生日前の出来事」！
Plus, the bonus voice "The Day Before My Birthday"!
これはですね、ちょっとラミィのあまあまなひとりごととかが色々入っておりまして、
In this one, Lamy's being all sweet and muttering to herself...
あの、これはですね、ぜひぜひみんなに聞いてほしいなと雪民さんにみんなに聞いてほしいなと思いますので、
I really want everyone—all my Yukimins—to listen to it,
ぜひぜひフルセットおまかせして、この特典ボイスを聞いてもらえると嬉しいです！
so I hope you'll get the full set and enjoy this bonus voice!
それではみんな、よろしくね！
Well then everyone, take care!
ありがとう！
Thank you!